

COMPUTER PROGRAMMER · SECURITY EXPER

Tehran, Iran

🛮 (+98) 912-634-9698 | 🗷 khaleghsalehi@gmail.com | 🌴 https://khalegh.net | 🖸 khaleghsalehi | 🛅 khaleghsalehi

Summary_

With 12+ years of experience specializing in software security and programming. core programmer and creator of 3 successful commercial software in the security field. A geek who loves open source, programming, and security. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools if the need arises.

Work Experience __

Ofogh Andisheh Group (OAG), Co.

Tehran, Iran

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

June. 2022 - Dec. 2022

• Developed the BoTTrack for Web Application DDoS attacks mitigation and API protection. With the accomplishment of the BoTTrack project, OAG successfully enhanced product and protection services and increased its profit by 60% in 2022.

Safe Instrument, Co.

Tehran, Iran

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

March. 2021 - Dec. 2022

Developed industrial firewall (AttackIQ) with a modular architecture (virtual patch, deep packet inspection, profiler, network layer DoS/DDoS mitigation, traffic filtering, industrial protocols recognition). Safe Instrument is an active company in the field of industry; It is proud to be the first domestic company with its own industrial firewall. Now, 90% of NIOC (National Iranian Oil Company) plants are protected by AttackIQ firewall.

SecLab, Telecommunication Research Center (ITRC)

Tehran, Iran

SECURITY EXPERT

Nov. 2021 - March. 2022

- Penetration tests and application security analysis and redesigned the SecLab testing procedures that enhanced testing quality and response time up to 400%
- · Mentoring juniors and help the assessment teams, that enhanced the quality of test results up to 80% in SecLab.

Innovera Tehran, Iran

SECURITY FREELANCER

February. 2019 - Nov. 2021

- Designed and developed IronFox (high-performance bot protection and DDoS defender) with a new approach for BOT detection and DDoS protection that guarantee %99 of accuracy in attack detection.
- Developed Higer for API protection. Higer is an Nginx module for API protection in full transparent mode with 0% change in the back-end code base and minimal configuration.
- · Performed penetration tests and code reviews for more than 10 companies (insurance and financial).

Smart Land Solutions (SLS)

Tehran,Iran

SECURITY EXPERT

January. 2017 - January. 2019

- Presented AppArmor SDK (Native API) for android applications protection, SLS mobile team successfully used the AppArmor in Android apps and the cost of security reduced up to 55K(USD) in project.
- Providing Security maintains, Penetration testing (Service, Infrastructures with more than (1,000 Virtual Machine) and mobile applications (with 12,000,000 active setup).
- Performed code reviews (4 active in-development project) and static source code analysis.

Amn Pardazan Sorena Tehran, Iran

SECURITY EXPERT

May. 2013 - January. 2017

- Delivered the LuFuzz (fuzzing framework) for security testing based on the fuzzing technique. LuFuzz becomes of the critical factors for Amn Pardazan Sorena, in order to become the Exemplary Entrepreneur (Rank 1) of IRAN in 2016.
- Developed ICAP (based on C-ICAP) module for encrypted traffic interception and content analyze.
- Performed penetration testing and member of CERT team (maintained by Amn Pardazan Sorena).

Fara System Novin (FSN)

Tabriz, Iran

SECURITY ASSISTANT

March. 2010 - May. 2013

- Preformed service hardening, Linux and web service maintenance(with up-time %99).
- Motivated and helped the teams shift to new platforms and open source-based services such as Apache, Linux, and MySQL. Migration to new technologies helped FSN team to reduced the cost of service maintenance and security up to 80%.

Honors & Awards

DOMESTIC

2000 **5Th national rank in robotics competitions**, Khwarizmi Awards

Zanjan,Iran

FEBRUARY 1, 2023 KHALEGH SALEHI · RÉSUMÉ



First CSUT Conference on Computer, Communication, Information Technology

Tabriz,Iran

PRESENTER Nov. 2011

• Introduced the Information Security and practical techniques for hacking and mitigation.

Education

University College of Daneshvaran

Tabriz, Iran

B.S. IN SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

Jan. 2008 - Jun. 2010

High Education School of ALQadir

Zanjan, Iran

A.S.C IN COMPUTER SOFTWARE TECHNOLOGY

Skills_

Software Security Software, Web Application, Mobile

Software Testing OWASP TOP 10, MITRE TOP 25, DAST, SAST, Security Code Review, Fuzzing

Cyber Security WAF, Firewall, IDS, Web Application Layer DDoS Protection, Threat Modeling, Security Protocols, CC(Common Criteria)

Back-end Spring Boot, REST API, Redis, Nginx, PostgreSQL

Penetration Testing Kali Linux, Metasploit, Burp Suite, Zap, Core Impact, Nessus, Security Scanners

Programming C, Java, Go, Python

Languages Azerbaijani, English, Turkish, Persian

Extracurricular Activity _____

Open Source Community

Tehran, Iran

DEVELOPER Sep. 2014 - Dec. 2023

- IronFox project, a real-time web application layer bot detection and DDoS protection.
- Higer module, Nginx module for real-time API and back-end protection.
- <u>TraffShield module</u>, a Netfilter module for TCP/IP layer DoS/DDoS attack protection.
- Knocker module , Netfilter module for service protection based on knocking technique.
- Batsapp, a full and open source Parental control system (with mobile app and back-end service).
- Nginx Anti-DDoS module, a High-performance DDoS protection module for Nginx based on browser fingerprinting. In the core of Anti-DDoS module with custom BoT detection technique, this module able to block 99% of automates security scanners, crawler and malicious bots.
- Cink tiny library as a fast memory cache (Key, Value storage) for embedded systems. Cink emphasize on speed and SET/GET keys with 0% of I/O latency.